SAHILPREET SINGH

♥ Ontario, Canada

Sahilpreetsingh9915545834@gmail.com

647-675-9915

SUMMARY

A full-stack web developer with rich experience in designing, developing, testing, innovating and deploying different website technologies. Key strengths include developing user-friendly websites, improving security, and collaborating with the team of developers. Adapt to learn towards new emerging technologies with a passion to build world-class websites.

SKILLS

• Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript, JAVA

Front-end: HTML, CSS, JS, React, Bootstrap,Back-end: NodeJS, Python, REST API, Django

•Database: SQL, MongoDB

•Front-end/Back-end Tooling: Version Control System, NPM & Yarn

•Other: Git, Selenium, Scrapy, Typescript

EXPERIENCE

ROGERS

BUSINESS SUPPORT TECHNICIAN

Ontario, Canada

July,2022 - Present

- Provided support to users regarding technical issues.
- Maintain the operations running by solving the technical issues.
- Speaking to customers to quickly get to the root of their problem.
- Following up with clients to ensure the problem is resolved.
- Providing support in the form of procedural documentation.
- Managing multiple cases at one time.
- Worked in a team of members from different nations

Web Developer

Punjab, India

Net Soft Lab

June 2019 – Aug 2020

- Developed an e-Commerce website to sell products online for a local seller. Increased the sales of a vendor by 25%.
- Integrated new features to an existing website using React which increased user experience of the website and make it responsive for mobile design.
- Make the backend faster by integrating new technologies using MERN stack which decrease the load time of a website by 50%.
- Automated scraping journal website using Scrapy, parsing and cleaning the data using Python.
- Tested many websites and removed bugs which not only decreased load time but strengthen security
 of websites.

EDUCATION

Lambton College

Mississauga, ON

Wireless Networking

2020 - 2022

Guru Nanak Dev University

BS, Computer Science

Amritsar, India 2016 – 2019

UDEMY

Remote

Javascript, Python, Web-Development, MERN

2022-2023

PROJECTS

Social Media website

https://react-chat-5xzz.onrender.com

Designed and developed a full-fledged social media web application using the MERN stack. Users can connect with friends, follow and unfollow their posts. Used REACT to develop the user-friendly interface and node to create REST API. Implemented secure user authentication with password hashing and session management. Currently in progress adding real time chat with WebSocket and many more features.

E-commerce website

https://sahil99155.pythonanywhere.com/

This website is made with Django at the backend and using REST API to interact with REACT at the front end. From writing Frontend CSS to developing the API in DJANGO in the Back-end all the website is designed and coded by me.

Demo Projects

https://github.com/sahilpreet

Developed the Flashkart website in the MERN stack. Using the Node as the backend and MongodB as storage, React as frontend and with packages of Express library with NPM to bundle it. Visit my GitHub profile to have a look at it.

WEBSITES

LinkedIn Profile https://www.linkedin.com/in/sahilpreet-singh-1b36b016b/

GitHub Profile https://github.com/sahilpreet